check-my-ip.net 2016-12-19

# Privacy Policy - Check My IP

Welcome to check-my-ip.net, the home of IP Geolocation and IP Resources for better IP related queries. This website was built to offer a to z solution on IPv4 addresses, and how it relates to TCP/IP and Internet. There are times when you need to identify where your web visitors are coming from. You might have an ecommerce website, and would like to know where your potential customers are, pre-populate country code on forms, display different language and reduce credit card fraud based on geographic location. Or, you might want to fight against illegal spammers and hackers, and would like to locate source of a problem. The major search engines such as Google, Yahoo and MSN/Bing are becoming ever more sophisticated and smart in their search algorithms, and incorporate historical and IP address data, it is now even more important than ever to ensure that you take the necessary precautions when designing a network of linked web sites. Also check and find out who your linking partners are, find where they are hosted and test what their IP Address is. This IP address checker will help you do that. The whois lookup will reveal name of the ISP who owns that IP address, and the country where it is originated from. If you're lucky, you might also find the city of origin. You may use 'traceroute' command to find clues to the location of the IP address. The names of the routers through which packets flow from your host to the destination host might hint at the geographical path of the final location. 

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at [Contact](mailto:forumrs3@gmail.com).

At http://www.check-my-ip.net/ we consider the privacy of our visitors to be extremely important. This privacy policy document describes in detail the types of personal information is collected and recorded by http://www.check-my-ip.net/ and how we use it. 

**Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, http://www.check-my-ip.net/ makes use of log files. These files merely logs visitors to the site - usually a standard procedure for hosting companies and a part of hosting services's analytics. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
http://www.check-my-ip.net/ does not use cookies. 

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**  
→ Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on http://www.check-my-ip.net/.  
→ Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our site's visitors based upon their visit to http://www.check-my-ip.net/ and other sites on the Internet.   
→ Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>

**Our Advertising Partners**  
Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include .......   

  * Google

_While each of these advertising partners has their own Privacy Policy for their site, an updated and hyperlinked resource is maintained here:[Privacy Policies](http://www.privacypolicyonline.com/privacy-policies).  
You may consult this listing to find the privacy policy for each of the advertising partners of http://www.check-my-ip.net/._

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology in their respective advertisements and links that appear on http://www.check-my-ip.net/ and which are sent directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by our site's third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on the site. 

http://www.check-my-ip.net/ has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

�

 **Third Party Privacy Policies**  
You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. http://www.check-my-ip.net/'s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. You may find a comprehensive listing of these privacy policies and their links here: [Privacy Policy Links](http://www.privacypolicyonline.com/privacy-policy-links "Privacy Policy Links").

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites. [What Are Cookies?](http://www.privacypolicyonline.com/what-are-cookies)

**Children's Information**  
We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to observe, participate in and/or monitor and guide their online activity. http://www.check-my-ip.net/ does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian believes that http://www.check-my-ip.net/ has in its database the personally-identifiable information of a child under the age of 13, please contact us immediately (using the contact in the first paragraph) and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records. 

**Online Privacy Policy Only**  
This privacy policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website and regarding information shared and/or collected there. This policy does not apply to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.

**Consent**  
By using our website, you hereby consent to our privacy policy and agree to its terms. 

**Update**  
This Privacy Policy was last updated on: Saturday, September 24th, 2016. [](http://www.privacypolicyonline.com/ "PrivacyPolicyOnline.com Approved Site")  
_Should we update, amend or make any changes to our privacy policy, those changes will be posted here._

1\. What is check-my-ip? check-my-ip is mapping of an IP address or MAC address to the real-world geographic location of an Internet connected to a computing device or mobile device. Geolocation involves in mapping IP address to the country, region (city), latitude/longitude, ISP and domain name among other useful things.   
2\. Where can I get a check-my-ip database? There are a number of commercially available geolocation databases, and their pricing and accuracy may vary. Ip2location, MaxMind, Tamo Soft and IPligence offer a fee based databases that can be easily integrated into an web application. Most geolocation database vendors offers APIs and example codes (in ASP, PHP, .NET and Java programming languages) that can be used to retrieve geolocation data from the database. We use Ip2Location database to offer a free geolocation data on our website. There are also freely available geolocation databases. Vendors offering commercial geolocation database also offer a Lite or Community edition that provides IP-to-Country mappings.   
3\. How accurate is check-my-ip? Accuracy of check-my-ip database varies depending on which database you use. For IP-to-country database, some vendors claim to offer 98% to 99% accuracy although typical Ip2Country database accuracy is more like 95%. For IP-to-Region (or City), accracy range anywhere from 50% to 75% if neighboring cities are treated as correct. Considering that there is no official source of IP-to-Region information, 50+% accuracy is pretty good.   
4\. How does check-my-ip work? ARIN Whois database provides a mechanism for finding contact and registration information for IP resources registered with ARIN. The IP whois information is available for free, and determining the country from this database is relatively easy. When an organization requires a block of IP addresses, a request is submitted and allocated IP addresses are assigned to a requested ISP. Another important and useful service from check-my-ip.net   
check-my-ip maintains a history of IP addresses for both known spammers as well as senders with good email practices. This information contributes to the check-my-ip Reputation System, which gives the check-my-ip Spam & Virus Firewall the ability to block or allow a message based on the sender's IP address. In addition to IP reputation, the check-my-ip team maintains reputation on URLs, which gives the check-my-ip Spam & Virus Firewall the ability to quickly block an email based on a poorly-rated URL contained in the message. By combining both the IP and reputation data, check-my-ip Networks can easily determine whether a message is spam or legitimate email. Once identified, check-my-ip can implement countermeasures to mitigate these threats.   
check-my-ip Reputation is one of the many techniques check-my-ip Networks employs within the check-my-ip Spam & Virus Firewall to reinforce its superior 95 percent spam accuracy rate. The check-my-ip Reputation System is a real-time database of IP addresses that have a "poor" reputation for sending valid emails. check-my-ip maintains and manually verifies all IP addresses marked as "poor" on the check-my-ip Reputation System. 

Disclaimer: There is nothing in the which is 100% accurate result orienting either virtual world or physical world, so there may a few data have differences with other contemporary data finders. 

Page generated in 0.0005 seconds.
